Exercise 2-18, Practicing Word Groups. When I read the paragraph this time, I'll
exaggerate the pauses. Although we're working on word groups here, remember, I
don't want you to lose your intonation. Repeat each sentence group after me.
Hello. My name is Anne. I'm taking American accent training. There's a lot to
learn, but I hope to make it as enjoyable as possible. I should pick up on the
American intonation pattern pretty easily although the only way to get it is to
practice all the time. I use the up and down or peaks and valleys intonation more
than I used to. I've been paying attention to pitch too. It's like walking down a
staircase. I've been talking to a lot of Americans lately and they tell me that I'm
easier to understand. Anyway I could go on and on, but the important thing is to listen
well and sound good. Well, what do you think? Do I? Next, practice the word
groups three times using strong intonation. When reading, your pauses
should be neither long nor dramatic, just enough to give your listener time to
digest what you're saying. Be sure to take a breath for each phrase, not for each
word, or indeed the entire paragraph.